MYA KHET WAI



80, Damayone Street, Ground Floor (right), Myaynigone, Sanchaung Township, Yangon, Myanmar. +95 (0) 989 792 9244 msmyakhetwai@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Repatriate, experienced & dedicated IT professional with over 13 years of experience across a variety of industries including web/software development, insurance, retail automotive, digital marketing, E-Commerce, and intergovernmental organization. Skilled in full-stack web development(agile/waterfall), database design and administration, data analysis and reporting, project and team management, and application/technical support

EDUCATION

Assumption University, Bangkok, Thailand

September 2008 – January 2012

Master of Information Science (Internet and E-Commerce Technology) (CGPA – 3.85/4.0)

University of Computer Studies, Yangon, Myanmar

April 2001 – June 2005

Bachelor of Computer Science (CGPA – 3.0/4.0)(Qualified to attend Honors Degree Program)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Development Specialist (National Consultant) | UNESCO Myanmar

1st Dec 2021 – 31st Oct 2023

- ✓ Exploring the possible LMS, CMS, and customized LMS solutions to propose the best option for developing the new E-learning system of the Myanmar Teacher Platform (MTP).
- ✓ Gathering requirements, analyzing technical specifications, developing, testing, deploying, and improving the MTP (https://mmteacherplatform.net/), which includes E-library and E-learning systems.
- ✔ Performing the integration of Zoom, ChatGPT, SCORM/xAPI, and Vonage SMS into the MTP.
- ✓ Developing comprehensive project plans, establishing clear roadmaps/work plans, and creating realistic timelines.
- ✓ Being responsible for finding the best contractor to develop, improve, and maintain the mobile applications of the MTP, creating APIs, and coordinating and managing the project.
- ✓ Preparing training materials and providing orientation sections to different groups of participants volunteering in the pilot testing (Phase I/web and Phase II/mobile) of the MTP.

- ✓ Communicating and coordinating with several support agents from software or cloud service vendors such as AWS, Digital Ocean, Vonage, and Click Send to resolve issues related to website functionalities or billing.
- ✓ Taking responsibility for user experience (UX) and user interface (UI) of the E-library/E-learning platforms to reach the unreached and promote flexible education.
- Providing any required IT support to ensure the success of the project team and generating monthly and ad-hoc reports.

Team Lead (Application Services & Management) | KBZMS General Insurance (Myanmar) 10th March 2020 – 31st May 2021

- ✓ Led a team of system analysts/analyst programmers to deliver the services related to applications used by internal users
- ✓ Managed the third-party vendors for setting up of products in the both legacy system (Tharmarwaddy) and new core PAS system (TCS Bancs)
- ✓ Made sure the change control process as per the agreements in the signed off contract
- ✓ Affirmed that the team to maintain the distributed databases, solve the database issues and respond to requests by business users from both HO and 18 branches
- ✓ Supporting business users by diagnosing, troubleshooting the raised issues and performing root cause analysis (L1 support for TCS Bancs and L1&L2 support for Tharmarwaddy)
- ✓ Assisted users in producing ad-hoc reports, monthly reports and output documents by applying advanced features of Jasper reports software. Also prepared the validated data ready to migrate to PowerBI for data analytic and risk management teams
- ✔ Performed research and proof of concept (POC) for new software, technology and automation tools and participated in personal and technical interviews as well
- ✔ Provided trainings for the team members, business users and vendors
- ✓ Got involved in analyzing and testing of issue tracking system (Odoo) in both SIT & UAT

Full-stack Developer | RMA Group Co.,Ltd (Thailand)

18th March 2019 – 28th February 2020

- ✓ Set up and configured Ubuntu Linux server with LAMP stack, FTP and mail servers using AWS EC2 and SES
- ✓ Implemented the chatbot admin panel to create a customized chatbot by using Laravel PHP framework and integrating with Facebook and line chatbot platforms (https://goautobot.chat/)
- ✓ Integrated Facebook reply to comment feature to chatbot app by applying graph API
- ✔ Prepared manual testing for the chatbot app and created video tutorials for both the Facebook developer team (in approving to grant permission process) and end users to assist in understanding the app better
- Developed customer websites using WordPress CMS and customized themes and plugins based on business requirements (https://mazdacity.co.th/, https://mazda3thailand.club/)

Team Lead (Software Development) | Heroleads Digital Marketing (Thailand)

2nd July 2018 – 8th March 2019

- ✓ Gathered requirements from business stakeholders and conducted usability tests to ensure the upcoming modules of Alpha (https://heroai.heroleads.co.th/), a cloud-based and customized Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) system, meet user needs. Alpha features role-based workflow management and is designed to replace several existing standalone systems.
- ✓ Analyzed Alpha system to find out the logic gaps, created user stories in Jira and participated/led the daily stand-up meeting via Skype with the development team in Vietnam
- ✓ Developed configuration Alpha modules using Angular 6 and Angular Material
- ✔ Performed POC for several JS graphic libraries to support the features and performance of viewing analytic data in Alpha
- ✓ Designed and developed APIs for permission control system using Laravel and MongoDB

Senior PHP Developer & Front-end Developer | Allianz Technology (Thailand)

1st April 2015 – 11th June 2018

- ✓ Got solid experience in the agile software development process by participating in Scrum/Kanban meetings and used project management tools such as Jira and Confluence.
- ✓ Created customized Google Maps functionality, user permission control, PDF reporting system, fixed security vulnerabilities and unit testing by using Symfony 2 PHP framework with Doctrine
- ✓ Converted user interface designed in PSD into responsive website by utilizing HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Bootstrap 3 and Ionic Frameworks
- ✓ Developed and maintained the front-end part of IOS hybrid application by using Cordova, Angular JS, Gulp and Node.js and performed unit testing with Karma-Jasmine framework
- ✓ Took part in developing the system based on pattern lab in designing atomic design patterns and in an internal HRM system which is built by applying Angular 2 and bootstrap 3 for front-end development

PHP Web Developer | In Asia Tour Co., Ltd (Thailand)

23rd June 2014 – 31st December 2014

- ✓ Achieved comprehensive experiences by developing an E-Commerce website and customized shopping cart system based on Codeigniter PHP framework, MySQL and Ajax
- ✓ Developed logging functionality and Like & Share capabilities with Facebook API
- ✓ Applied payment system by integrating PayPal API and learnt to utilize Tripadvisor API and widgets
- ✓ Modified logos and converted PSD to HTML template for the company websites: (https://www.thailandholidays24.com, https://www.laosholidays24.com, https://www.burmaholidays24.com, https://www.cambodiaholidays24.com)

System Developer | Crescere Thailand(Thailand)

1st February 2013 – 30th April 2014

- ✓ Got extensive experiences in PHP, MySQL and Ajax while developing invoice system, dictionary system and password keeping system
- ✓ Designed pdf invoices using FPDF library and attached them with emails by using swift mail
- ✓ Also had a chance to develop a website using WordPress (https://www.tradthai.com)
- ✓ Developed full text search system by applying Amazon web services and Asp.net as well as banner/stamp printing system by using iTextSharp pdf library and Asp.net using VB

✓ Managed to integrate logging in with social networking sites like Twitter, LinkedIn, Google Plus by utilizing the respective APIs

PHP Programmer | E-Motion Bangkok (Thailand)

1st February 2012 – 31st January 2013

- ✓ Applied Dqer PHP5 framework in developing Leadbridges ICRM software and MySQL on Linux platform and also contributed in testing and debugging the software
- ✓ Got a chance to work closely with the developer of Dger PHP5 framework, Mr.Victor Gatkov
- ✔ Developed and integrated payment system APIs of BrainTree, Recurly, PayPal and Subscription Bridge using PHP and XML techniques
- ✓ Had experiences in designing email templates and integrating OSTicket ticketing system

IT Administrator/Web Developer | Mercato Holdings Limited (Thailand)

25th March 2010 – 31st January 2012

- ✔ Purchased and listed products for the online E-commerce store, and communicated with customers via email
- ✓ Took product photographs, edited them using Photoshop, and managed shipping via Thai Post to Europe
- ✓ Additionally, prepared income and expenditure reports
- ✓ Developed and maintained company website (https://www.labeltune.com)
- ✓ Implemented SEO strategies and conducted link building activities

FREELANCE WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer | Self-employed

August 2018 – Dec 2018

- ✓ Developed a travel and rental website using Angular 6
- ✓ Integrated social media plugins such as Facebook and Google
- ✓ Implemented APIs using NodeJS, Express JS, Mongoose JS, MongoDB (Mean stack), and ngx-admin admin theme
- ✓ Took care of designing, developing, and deploying on the web server of the stalwartlab.com WordPress website

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- ✔ Programming Languages: PHP (OOP including PHP Frameworks like Laravel (5,7,8), Dqer, Codelgniter, Symfony 2), JavaScript (including AngularJS, Angular (2, 5, 6), Node.js, jQuery) Asp.net (VB), C, C++, Java 2, Python
- ✓ Content Management Systems (CMS): WordPress, Joomla
- ✓ Learning Management Systems (LMS): Moodle
- ✓ Version Control: Git, SVN
- ✓ Frontend Development Tools: Bootstrap (3, 4, 5), CSS3, SCSS, Grunt, Gulp
- ✓ Databases:
 - o RDBMS: MySQL, MS SQL, Oracle
 - o NoSQL: MongoDB
 - o **ORM:** Doctrine, Eloquent

- ✓ Data Collection & Analysis: KoboToolbox, LimeSurvey, DHIS2, Microsoft Excel, Power BI, Google Analytics
- ✓ Software & Tools: Visual Studio Code, Sublime Text, Microsoft Word, Microsoft PowerPoint, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD, Canva
- ✓ Cloud Computing: AWS (hands-on experience in deploying EC2 instances, DNS management using Route 53, implementing security best practices for EC2, and reliable mail forwarding)
- ✓ Web Standards: HTML 4.0, XHTML 1.1, HTML 5, CSS 2, CSS 3, XML
- ✓ Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP): Odoo, Alpha (customized ERP for Heroleads Digital Marketing)
- ✔ Platforms: Windows 11, macOS, Linux (Ubuntu, CentOS)
- ✓ Others: SEO, Integration of Social Networking Plugins, API development and LMS integrations via SCORM and xAPI

LANGUAGE SKILLS

- ✔ Burmese: Native Speaker
- ✓ English: Proficient in four skills (worked in English-speaking environments for the past 12 years, TOEFL: Scored 620/677 (Paper-Based Test, 2006))
- ✓ Thai: Basic in all four skills

ACTIVITIES AND AWARDS

- Srisakdi Charmonman Certificate of Honour (2012): Awarded by Prof. Dr. Srisakdi Charmonman, Assumption University of Thailand
- Certificate of Service (2008): Awarded by Save the Children Girls Scholarship Program, Yangon, Burma

LICENSES AND CERTIFICATIONS

- ✓ Design User Experiences with Figma (2024): Issued by Linkedin Learning on Jul, 2024, Credential Link: https://www.linkedin.com/learning/certificates/61912e17fcbba8047eb69d41 3d3c415dfa44bdfbc5ea72fca99d4e1fef6eb377
- Advance Your Skills in WordPress (2024): Issued by Linkedin Learning on Jul, 2024, Credential Link: https://www.linkedin.com/learning/certificates/f021c4ecb889b6e0d95b438c43 702b3aa73f7282b356d64f5c7563762f0049bf
- ✓ Career Essentials in Generative AI by Microsoft and LinkedIn (2024): Issued by Microsoft and LinkedIn on Jun, 2024, Credential Link: https://www.linkedin.com/learning/certificates/9a0eb03e845eb667897f2873305db6f58dc9cf5569c81acf0d13bbd055e60dc3
- ✓ AWS Cloud Quest: Cloud Practitioner (2024): Issued by Amazon Web Services(AWS) on Jan, 2024, Credential Link: https://www.credly.com/badges/c54b2b90-243f-4945-a920-acfca401f429
- ✓ AWS Knowledge: Cloud Essentials (2024): Issued by Amazon Web Services(AWS) on Jan, 2024 Credential Link: https://www.credlv.com/badges/836e2067-30e9-4e67-ad8c-09dffaaa696e/
- ✓ Course Completion Certificate of "Ultimate AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate SAA-C03": Issued via Udemy on Mar, 2024
 Credential Link: https://www.udemv.com/certificate/UC-91f73342-eaad-4ce4-b001-f22f5f56c3f0/

✓ Course Completion Certificate of "COBIT® 2019 Foundation - official, accredited": Issued via Udemy on Mar, 2024, Credential Link: https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-d73e59df-45b1-4bd6-9d91-9a50af1c0a81/